[ Static crackling ]
[ Device clicks , whirs ]
So , it 's becoming more apparent
that not only is Gabriel getting stronger ,
he 's becoming more malicious .
If his strength and ability continue to grow at this rate ,
we will no longer be able to contain him .
However , I am still determined ...
[ Lights buzzing ]
[ Door opens ]
Man : Dr. Weaver , he got out again .
- How far did he get this time ? - He made it to the records room
before we got to him . He found his information .
He wants to go home .
[ Electricity buzzing and warbling ]
Dr. Fields , what the hell is happening ?
I tried to subdue him with ect ,
but electroshock had no effect on him .
Then all the machines started going crazy .
It was like he was drinking the electricity
- and controlling our machines . - [ Alarm blaring ]
[ Screams ]
- Dr. Weaver : Dr. Plume . - [ Muffled screeching ]
[ Muffled snarling ]
No , please , don 't . He 'll kill you .
- Stand aside . - [ Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
Take him down now .
- [ Cocks gun ] - — [ Alarm continues blaring ]
- — [ Inhuman screeching ] - [ Screams ]
[ Flesh squelching ] — [ Yelping ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Nurse screaming ] — [ Lights bursting ]
[ Sinister music playing ]
[ Eerie scream ]
[ High-pitched screeching ]
[ Body thuds ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Ominous music playing ]
Strap him into the chair .
You 've been a bad , bad boy , Gabriel .
[ Gabriel snarling ]
[ Electronic feedback whining ]
Gabriel : [ Distorted ] I will kill you all .
Oh , my god . He speaks .
He 's broadcasting his thoughts .
I thought we could help him , but I was wrong .
[ Snarling ]
It 's time
we cut out the cancer .
[ Dramatic music playing ]
[ Dramatic music continues ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Soft music playing ]
[ Groans softly ]
[ Muffled sports commentary on TV ]
Announcer : Frankie is trying to get to Chavez .
He 's trying to get his arms up to protect himself ,
but he can 't get any leverage .
Hey , sugar , I thought you were on the late shift .
I was , but dumpling 's been giving me a really hard time .
[ Madison groans ]
What do you mean , " a hard time " ?
I don 't know .
She 's just a little more agitated than usual .
Do we have any Tylenol ?
They say I can 't take aspirin .
[ Pills rattling ]
You know , if you 've got all this pain ,
maybe you shouldn 't be going to work .
[ Sighs ] I 'll be fine . I promise .
Hey , I was watching that .
Please , Derek , I really need to get some rest .
No , maybe you need to stop getting pregnant .
Derek , please . I just really need to lie down .
You know the doctor said
this could happen again , right ?
You know that .
How many times do I have to watch
my children die inside of you ?
Just stop .
You 're breaking my heart , maddy . I swear to god .
You can 't keep doing this .
[ Low ominous music playing ]
Doing what ?
Doing what , Madison ? Tell me what I 'm doing , huh ?
Tell me what I 'm doing .
Are you saying this is my fault ?
Are you saying this keeps happening because of ...
Don 't touch her !
- You bitch ! - [ Madison grunts ]
[ Whimpers ]
Oh , shit .
Oh , baby , I 'm so sorry .
[ Madison wincing ]
I 'm gonna get you some ice , okay ?
Okay , I 'm gonna get you some ice . Hold on .
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Shudders ]
[ Gasping ]
- [ { door thuds ] - [ Gasps ]
[ Door rattling ]
Derek : Babe ,
I 'm sorry that happened , that , uh ...
Sometimes it 's like I can 't control myself , okay ?
But that 's not me , that ...
You know , I 'm trying , and I 've given up drinking ,
and I 'm gonna continue to do better
- for you and the baby , okay ? - [ Sobs ]
Maddy ? Please . [ Sighs ]
It was an accident , maddy .
[ Crying softly ]
[ Breathing raggedly ]
[ Metallic rattling ]
Maddy ?
[ Breathes deeply ]
[ Muffled rattling ]
[ Low ominous music playing ]
[ Rattling continues ]
[ Machine whirring ]
[ Door opens and creaks ]
What ?
Madison ?
[ Static whining and crackling ]
Man on TV : It cannot be !
Woman : Grabbed a steel blade .
Man 2 : Has possession of the puck down ...
[ Engine roaring on TV ]
Man 3 : Just now crossed paths out of ...
- [ { men on TV whooping ] - [ Gunshots on TV ]
Help me .
[ Static whining ]
[ Soft eerie music playing ]
[ High-pitched electrical ringing ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Groans ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Grunting weakly ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Groans ]
- [ Muffled thud ] - [ Gasps ]
Derek ?
[ Gasps ]
[ Sinister music playing ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Eerie music playing ]
[ Heavy breathing ]
[ Bones cracking ]
[ Wheezes ]
[ Inhuman screeching ]
[ Madison screams ]
[ Tense music playing ]
[ Madison whimpering ]
[ Yelps ]
- [ Helicopter whirring ] - [ Indistinct radio chatter ]
[ Sirens wailing ]
[ Indistinct police radio chatter ]
Morning , reg .
Morning ? It 's 4 am . Night 's not even over yet .
- Detectives . - Officer Lee ,
what happened here ?
Home invasion .
Neighbors heard screaming and called it in .
Regina : Any sign of forced entry ?
Officer Lee : Not that we 've seen .
- Where 's the wife ? - Already at the hospital .
We found her unconscious in the nursery .
Uh-oh , here comes miss lonely-heart .
- Hey , kekoa . - Winnie , how bad is it ?
I 've never seen anything quite like it .
Maybe from a vehicular accident , but not this .
This is something special .
Holy shit .
[ Machine beeping ]
[ Muffled chattering ]
[ Groans softly ]
Madison : [ Softly ] Sydney ?
Where am I ? What ... what happened ?
It 's okay . You 're in a hospital .
Where 's Derek ?
Do you remember what happened ? Someone broke into your house .
You were attacked , and Derek ...
[ Crying ] I was ...
- Just ... just rest . - I was ...
[ Continues crying ] I was so scared .
Scared for my baby .
[ Gasps ]
Where is she ?
Where is she , Syd ? Where is she ?
I 'm so sorry , maddy . They couldn 't save her .
[ Crying ] No .
No , no , no . No . No .
[ Wailing ]
It 's okay .
No ! Please , no .
[ Screams ] No !
Hey , okay .
[ Knock on door ]
Kekoa : Mrs. Mitchell ?
Mrs. Mitchell , I 'm detective kekoa Shaw .
I 'm sorry to bother you ,
but I need to ask you a few questions .
Mrs. Mitchell ?
Sydney : Can I help you with something ?
Uh , I 'm detective kekoa Shaw .
Oh , I 'm Sydney lake . I 'm Madison 's sister .
So , can I help you ?
Oh , this .
Um , I 'm a ... A Princess at family planet .
So , I 'm on my lunch break ,
and I thought I 'd come by and check on maddy .
She 's been like this for two days .
I can 't even get her to eat .
Well , maybe you can help me then .
Did you know of anyone who wanted
to hurt your sister or her husband ?
There 's no sign of forced entry at the house .
May have been somebody they knew .
Somebody with access .
I wouldn 't know . Derek kept us apart .
This isn 't her first , right ?
The doctor said your sister
had three miscarriages in the last two years .
Oh , my god .
Um , I didn 't know .
I don 't know why she wouldn 't have told me .
[ Softly ] Maddy ...
If there 's anything , just give me a call .
Yeah . Thank you .
Regina : Keh , you 'll get a kick out of this .
No fingerprints , but all the hand patterns are upside down .
Like our perp was hanging from the ceiling .
That line up with anything from forensics ?
No footprints on the ceiling , if that 's what you mean .
But I spoke to the neighbors , and more than one of them said
that Mr. Mitchell used to knock Mrs. Mitchell around .
He beat her ?
No forced entry , an abusive husband .
Motive .
Sydney : Please let me stay with you for a few days .
I can blow off work , and a few auditions .
It 's not like I 'm booking anything anyway .
[ Sighs ]
It felt so real this time .
[ Sighs deeply ]
I just ...
I just couldn 't do enough to protect her .
You don 't have to stay here , you know .
Madison : I know , but this is my home ,
and I 'm not gonna let it be taken away from me too .
I 'll be fine , I promise . [ Sniffling ]
[ Soft eerie music playing ]
[ Exhales deeply ]
[ Streetlight buzzing ]
[ Buzzing continues ]
[ Eerie music playing ]
[ Lights buzzing ]
[ Tense music playing ]
[ Lock clicks ]
[ Gasps ]
- [ Wind whistling ] - [ Door creaking ]
[ Object clatters ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Knocking ]
[ Water dripping ]
- [ { door thuds ] - [ Gasps ]
[ Door creaking ]
[ Madison whimpering ]
[ Tense music continues ]
[ Continues whimpering ]
[ Panting ] There 's nobody there .
There 's no one there .
It 's all in my head . It 's all in my head .
There 's no one there . It 's all in my ...
It 's all in my head .
[ Water dripping ]
[ Clock ticking ]
[ Light fizzes ]
[ Unnerving music playing ]
[ Tense music playing ]
[ Drill whirring ]
[ Door rattles ]
[ Keys jangling ]
[ Soft eerie music playing ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ] Oh , my god .
- Hey , are you gonna let me in ? - [ Sighs ]
Jesus , Sydney , what are you doing ?
[ Grunts ] Okay . My key wasn 't working and you weren 't ...
Oh , god .
You weren 't answering .
I thought something was wrong , I was worried .
[ Exhales heavily ]
Oh , I , um , installed deadbolts .
[ Sighs in relief ] That makes so much sense .
Well , okay .
Mom made a casserole .
I could not climb with it , so it is outside , but ,
you okay ?
He smashed my head against the wall .
What ?
I 'm so sorry , maddy .
Nobody deserves to die that way ,
but seriously , fuck him .
You deserve so much better .
I thought about it a lot , about leaving him .
By the time I got the courage , I got pregnant .
Now , if only I 'd been able to have a baby .
Don 't do that . This is not your fault .
That 's not what I 'm saying .
I wanted to know what it felt like
to have a blood connection with someone .
A biological connection .
Maddy , what are you talking about ?
[ Sighs ] Shit .
Mom and dad took me in when I was eight .
I don 't remember anything before that .
Mom told me that my biological mother died during my birth .
Sydney , I 'm adopted .
[ Dark dramatic music playing ]
Woman : Welcome to the Seattle underground .
No , folks , this is not a historical tour
- of nirvana or Pearl jam . - [ Laughter ]
This is a tour of old Seattle ,
buried underneath here
like a time capsule of a bygone era .
All this used to be at street level
where the people worked and lived .
But after the great fire of 1889 ,
they decided to rebuild the new city
on top of the old city .
One story higher to stave off flooding .
You can still see the cobblestone streets
and the storefronts down here .
And there are rumors of passages stretching for miles .
Some say the ghosts of the past
still haunt these tunnels .
[ Lights buzzing ]
[ Tourists murmuring ]
[ Chuckles ]
- [ Spookily ] Ooh . — [ Laughter ]
Thank you .
Thank you . Have a good night .
[ Cash register dings ]
[ Metal clatters ]
We 're closed .
[ Water dripping ]
[ Clanging ]
You can 't be down here .
Hello ?
- — [ Clanging ] - [ Gasps ]
- [ { heavy clang ] - [ Gasps ]
[ Growl ]
[ Panting ]
[ Tense music playing ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Lights buzzing ]
[ Muffled clattering ]
[ Eerie yowling ]
[ Screeches ]
[ Woman screams ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Dark dramatic music playing ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Muffled screaming ]
[ Stops screaming ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Muffled screaming ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Electronic feedback whines ]
Gabriel : [ On radio ] I can 't tell you
how long
I 've waited for this .
But not yet .
First ,
Dr. Weaver .
[ Whimpers ]
[ Phone ringing ]
[ Phone beeps ]
Dr. Weaver : Hello ?
Hello ?
- Gabriel [ over phone ] : Dr. Weaver . - Yes ?
Gabriel : It 's time to cut out the cancer .
What ?
Hello ? I 'm sorry , who is this ?
Hello ?
[ Keypad beeping ]
[ Ballad music playing ]
Man : [ Singing ] Too fast to live
too young to die
[ music continues on radio ]
One stolen kiss , babe
a certain smile
[ lights buzzing ]
[ Distorted ] We ' re never close , babe
[ { static crackling ] — [ Groans ]
[ Static and distortion stop ]
I 'm lost inside , babe
your painted smile
[ Sighs ]
- [ High — pitched screech ] - [ Gasps ]
[ High-pitched electrical ringing ]
[ Groans ]
- [ Wincing ] — [ Ringing stops ]
Shit .
[ Low unnerving music playing ]
- [ Screaming ] — [ Madison gasps ]
What are you doing in my house ?
This is my house !
Who are you ?
- [ Breathing shakily ] - [ High-pitched ringing ]
I can 't move . What 's happening ?
What do you want ? Who are you ?
[ Yelping ]
No ! [ Yelps ] No !
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Rustling ]
[ Madison gasping ]
[ Electronic feedback whining ]
Gabriel : Time to cut out the cancer .
Oh , god . No . It 's not possible .
[ Yelps ]
[ Groans ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Groaning and panting ]
[ Rousing music playing ]
[ Breathing rapidly ]
Oh , god .
[ Screams ]
What do you want from me ?
Gabriel : To show you what the cancer has become .
[ Screams ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Groans ]
[ Police siren wailing ]
Hey .
So , housekeeper found our Vic . Dr. Florence Weaver .
Tough old bird , but she fought until the end .
What you got , winnie ?
He killed her with one of her trophies .
We just got the base . The top half is missing .
The brutality seems consistent with our other corpse .
- Same guy ? - That would be my bet .
We need to find that missing half .
[ Chuckles shyly ] Yeah , don 't we all .
What you got ?
Dr. Weaver specialized in child reconstructive surgery .
She kept journals on all her patients .
Bag all these books .
I want them back at the precinct .
Yes , sir .
What , are you gonna go through all of them ?
We 're gonna go through all of them .
Hey , did you find the rest of that murder weapon yet ?
[ Rousing music playing ]
[ Rousing music continues ]
- [ { tool pounding ] - [ Gasps ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Muffled grunting ]
[ Yelps ]
Gabriel : Don 't even try .
News anchor : Breaking news this hour ,
as police are reporting the body
- of Dr. Florence Weaver ... - [ Retching ]
Was found brutally murdered
in her Washington park home this morning .
The grisly discovery was made by the housekeeper
at approximately 8 : 30 this morning .
[ Madison groaning and panting ]
Did you know her ?
But I saw her die .
I don 't know how .
I was doing laundry and ...
And I saw him killing her .
It was him . It was him .
Him ? Him , like the guy that attacked you ?
He was here in the ...
No , no .
I saw him murdering her in her house .
And it was like I was there and here at the same time .
It was ... it was ... What is happening to me , Syd ?
[ Softly ] Okay , okay .
[ Sobbing ]
It 'll be okay . We 're gonna figure it out , okay ?
[ Sighs ]
Ooh . [ Sighs ]
That 's it . I 'm out .
I read about one more sick kid ,
my brain 's gonna push out my eyeballs .
- Good night . - Tell Marcus it 's my fault .
I 'll make up for date night .
Regina : You better . He 's pissed .
[ Kekoa groans ]
Jesus .
- Yo , basco , you here ? - No .
- [ Thunder rumbles ] - I thought I was the only
good-looking guy here working late .
Got this case . Strange one . Can you age that up ?
How old do you need ?
30 years .
[ Thunder rumbling ]
I know , I know .
But who would kill her , John ?
Let alone mutilate her like that ?
I know , I haven 't spoken with her in years ,
but the person I knew , all she ever did was help people .
[ Man speaking indistinctly on phone ]
Don 't bring up simion .
That was a different time .
[ Static warbles on phone ]
Hello ? John ?
[ Wind howling ]
[ Soft eerie music playing ]
[ Door creaking ]
[ Wind howling ]
[ Sinister music plays ]
[ Low unnerving music playing ]
[ Thunder crackling ]
[ Lights buzzing ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Sinister music playing ]
[ Screams ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Whimpering softly ]
[ Rustling ]
- [ Thunder continues rumbling ] - [ High-pitched ringing ]
[ Sinister music continues ]
[ Whimpering softly ]
[ Screams ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Gabriel breathing heavily ]
[ Grunts , snarls ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Whimpering ]
- Maddy ? Maddy . Maddy . — [ Shrieks ]
Hey , what 's wrong ? What 's wrong ? What 's wrong ?
- He 's here . He 's here . - Who ? Who ?
[ Gasping ]
There 's no one here .
Look at me , there 's no one here .
You were just dreaming . Come here .
Shit , maddy , you 're bleeding .
I wasn 't dreaming .
I saw him . I saw him .
He killed again , but this time I saw his face .
I saw ... I saw his face .
Madison : Somehow I 'm seeing his murders ,
like he 's showing them to me .
What do you mean ? He 's sending you videos ?
No , goddamn it . I see them as they 're happening .
Like I 'm having visions . I know how that sounds .
Okay , maybe , when the killer attacked Madison ,
they formed , like , some kind of , um ,
like a ... a psychic bond .
I mean , you guys consult psychics for , like ,
missing persons cases , right ?
No , we don 't .
I played a psychic in an episode of a cop show ,
and they said it 's a real thing .
Are we really having this conversation ?
[ Kekoa clears throat ]
Okay , Madison , what exactly did you see ?
He killed again .
This time , across from the silvercup apartments
in north beacon hill .
- I googled it . - Great .
Wikipedia brown here just solved the case .
Listen , Madison saw Dr. Weaver die as it happened ,
and now she says she 's seen this one , so let 's go look .
If she 's wrong , you can have her committed ,
and you can put the cuffs on me .
[ Clears throat ]
[ Upbeat suspenseful music playing ]
There it is . Silvercup .
I think it 's this one .
Which one ?
So what , are we gonna knock on every door now ?
It 's the top floor .
We could help .
Yeah , we don 't need your help .
Could you keep an eye on these two ?
Come on , keh .
Sorry to bother you , ma 'am .
What ?
I see you .
What ? They gave us a lead .
Cute little actress throw you a ball ,
and you gone chasing like a dog .
- What was that ? - Nothing .
Hello ? Anybody home ? This is the police .
If anybody 's here , you need to let us know .
[ Kekoa sighs ]
[ Sinister music playing ]
So I 'm putting out a bolo on sloth from the goonies ?
- You okay ? Okay . - I 'm gonna go to the bathroom .
Reg ...
Um , you wanna take a seat while she ... while you wait ?
Oh , yeah .
[ Groaning ]
[ Cell phone vibrating ]
[ Static crackles ]
Hello ?
Gab ri El : Hello , Emily .
[ Sinister music playing ]
[ Breathes shakily ]
My name is Madison .
Gabriel : Your fake mother gave you the name Madison .
Your shitty marriage gave you the name Mitchell .
But you 'll always be Emily to me .
Who are you ?
Gabriel : You know who I am .
Even if they say I 'm only in your head .
I don 't know what you 're talking about .
You let them tell you I wasn 't real ,
that I was just a voice .
And you believed them .
Now , I 'm going to make them pay for what they did .
One by one .
Gabriel , no !
[ Gabriel laughing wickedly ]
[ Gasps ]
- Deep down ... - Please .
- You 've always known . - Please .
Please stop . Please .
Gabriel : Oh , we are just getting started .
[ Static crackles ]
[ Phone beeps ]
[ Exhales sharply ]
[ Indistinct chatter ]
Uh , detective , if we 're done here ,
- we 're leaving . Thank you . - Um ...
Okay . All right , well , I 'm ...
I 'll see you around , okay ?
Hey , hey , hey , you finish aging that photo ?
Yeah , I left it on your desk . You saw it , right ?
That 's why you brought her in .
- Brought who in ? - The girl in the picture .
Kekoa : Ah , hell .
She was the doctor 's patient .
What ? We 've gotta turn around and tell kekoa .
We can trace the call .
The cops think I did it .
Well , this will prove them wrong .
His name is Gabriel .
I don 't know how I knew ,
but talking to him , I just did .
He 's someone from my past .
From before I could remember .
[ Madison breathing heavily ]
Where are we going ?
Oh , maddy .
Maddy .
- I just had to see you . - Oh .
How are you holding up , sweetie , hmm ? Are you eating ?
You look skinny . I gotta cook more .
Mom , I need you to remember .
During the adoption , did they say
if I had a brother or anything ?
[ Faltering ]
The only thing they would say is if there were siblings ,
they try to place them in the same family .
Then who the hell is Gabriel ?
[ Ominous music playing ]
[ Breathing shakily ]
Madison : Mom ? Mom , what do you know ?
Frank and Jeanne : [ Singing ] Happy birthday ...
You wanted a party so bad , maddy ,
you nagged us until your father gave in .
We invited your whole class but ...
They thought I was a freak .
I had no friends . I remember that .
Frank : Birthday , dear maddy ...
Happy birthday to you
blow it out , blow it out .
[ Frank and Jeanne cheering ]
[ Laughs ]
Frank : Those look good . Looks good .
Stop saying that .
They are .
Maddy , who are you talking to ?
No one .
Frank : Maddy ? Maddy , what did we say about lying ?
I wasn 't .
Well , then who were you talking to ?
Gabriel .
Is he your imaginary friend ?
Gabriel isn 't made up .
He says that you are .
He says you 're not my real family .
- This is the nightmare that ... - Jeanne : Okay .
Ooh , that 's a kick .
- [ Laughs ] — frank : Ooh .
My little Christmas cutie right here .
- Go get her ready for bed . - Fran k : Okay .
Maddy , playtime 's over .
Santa won 't come down the chimney if you 're still up .
Mommy said she 'd love me when the baby comes .
She said nothing would change .
I won 't .
You can 't make me .
Please don 't hurt the baby .
Frank : Maddy ? What 's going on ?
Nothing , daddy .
Some of the conversations you had with Gabriel
just chilled us to the bone .
Wait , so Gabriel was something that I made up ?
Whatever you went through before you joined our family ,
it hurt you in a way that I can 't even imagine .
I always figured you created Gabriel
so that you could survive that .
We thought if we gave you enough love ,
you wouldn 't need him anymore .
I hope we weren 't wrong .
[ Sniffles ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Low foreboding music playing ]
Kekoa : E. May ...
Thursday , July 23rd , 1992 .
Today marks the seventh year
since Emily may was entrusted into our care .
She remains unlike any test subject
we have ever encountered here at the clinic .
Though in recent months , Emily started
exhibiting signs of mental psychosis .
She says she 's seeing visions ,
and hearing thoughts from the devil .
I 've contacted Dr. John Gregory out at Hopkins
as well as Dr. Victor fields
from the Los Angeles children 's hospital ,
just to help determine a course of action .
Kekoa : Dr. Florence Weaver . Dr. Victor fields .
Working the same case
along with Dr. John Gregory .
Holy shit .
[ Madison gasping ]
[ Rustling ]
- [ Lights buzzing ] - [ Breathing shakily ]
[ Siren wailing ]
Dr. Gregory ? This is Seattle pd .
[ Muffled thud ]
[ Gun clicks ]
I need you to answer me .
[ Gasps ]
[ Sinister music playing ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Heart thumping rapidly ]
Detective ! He 's still here .
He 's still here .
Oh , Jesus .
[ Blade rings ]
- [ { snarls ] - [ Gasping ]
[ Screams ]
[ Both grunting ]
[ Kekoa grunts ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Groans ]
[ Pained grunting ]
[ Panting ] Holy shit .
[ Panting heavily ]
[ Grunts ] I gotta be out of my mind .
[ Kekoa grunts ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Pained grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
- Kekoa : Stop ! - [ Gunshot ]
[ Heavy thud ]
[ Water trickling ]
[ Panting ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Eerie music playing ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Panting ]
[ Creaking ] — [ Gabriel yells ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Gasping ]
Fuck me .
[ Panting ]
All three victims were involved
in the same case study they called patient may .
You were the case study . They were your doctors .
Uh , I 'm sorry .
It 's all blank before Sydney 's parents adopted me .
I think you were born Emily may .
That 's what he calls me .
Madison ,
the department works with a hypnotherapist
that helps unlock repressed memories .
Trauma , sexual abuse , PTSD .
Would you be willing to see one ?
I knew it .
Regina : She 's not a psychic , god damn it .
[ Sydney clears throat ]
Hypnotherapist : We are gonna turn back the hands of time .
The bygone years reconstructing themselves .
I want you to go back to before the adoption .
[ Breathing heavily ] I think I 'm in a hospital .
But I don 't remember any of it .
Okay , you 've gone back
beyond your conscious memories .
Can you tell us why you 're in the hospital ?
[ Thunder rumbling ]
I 'm not sure .
But I 'm better now .
That 's why they 're here for me .
Hypnotherapist : Who ? Madison : My new parents .
They 've come to take me to my new home .
It 's nice .
But he 's here too .
Gabriel .
He followed me home from the hospital .
Who is Gabriel ? Is he a friend ?
He says he is , but I 'm the only one that can see him .
Frank : You ruined your mother 's cake .
- I didn 't , it was Gabriel . - Stop .
You can 't keep lying like this , maddy .
- I 'm not lying . - There 's no Gabriel .
Go to your room . Madison , go to your room right now .
Madison : So when he does something bad ,
I 'm the one that gets in trouble .
[ Crying ]
[ Phone ringtone playing ]
[ Sniffles ] — [ Ringing continues ]
Go away .
What ?
But she 's sleeping .
I guess .
Really ? You mean like a good surprise ?
[ Soft suspenseful music playing ]
Female voice : [ Whispers ] Cut it .
Male voice : [ Whispers ] A nice slice of cake for mom .
[ Rustling ]
[ Voices continue whispering indistinctly ]
[ Gasps ]
Madison !
Male voice : Cut her !
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ] No , it wasn 't me ! It was Gabriel !
Please ! No , no !
Please believe me !
Please !
Stop this . Stop this . Stop this !
Get her out , get her out ! Get her out !
[ Madison screaming ]
- Stop this . Stop this . - Kekoa : Beverly ...
- Bevedy ! - Get her out right now !
When I touch your forehead , you will be back with us .
[ Stops screaming ]
[ Gasps deeply ]
- [ Panting ] - Hey . Okay ?
- Maddy ? - [ Wheezes ]
Jesus .
Are you okay ?
I remember now .
It 's happened before ,
waking up in strange places ,
seeing things .
I don 't know how , but Gabriel wanted to ...
[ Madison sighs ]
What did he want , Madison ?
To hurt the baby .
It 's as if he knew that with you here ...
I wouldn 't need him anymore .
And he was right .
He became a lost memory ,
buried deep in the back of my head ...
Until now .
The killer said he was Gabriel .
My Gabriel .
Wait , are you saying that the killer is
your imaginary friend ?
[ Thunder rumbling ]
[ Sirens wailing in distance ]
[ Woman grunting ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Dark dramatic music playing ]
[ Sirens wailing ]
[ Dark dramatic music continues ]
Sydney : Everything 's gonna be okay .
Maddy ? Maddy , listen .
Wait . Please .
Detective , wait . Please .
I don 't know what 's going on ,
but maddy couldn 't have done this .
You can 't come back . This is a crime scene now .
- Please just listen to me . - No , you listen .
Back off , or I 'm gonna charge you
with being an accomplice .
[ Panting ]
Please .
Hey , you guys gotta see this .
[ Ominous music plays ]
It 's the rest of the missing trophy ,
fashioned into a weapon .
I told you , from day one .
You got the murder weapon , the coat , the gloves ,
and Jeffrey dahmer 's workshop in your attic .
It 's over , Madison .
It was ... it was Gabriel .
He got into my house . He 's done it before .
Enough with the bogeyman story .
Please , kekoa . Please .
You 've seen him .
You know that it 's not me .
- Who is the woman , Madison ? - I don 't know .
Gabriel must have snuck her into my house .
Regina : Let me tell you what I think .
You were sick in the head when you were young .
Those doctors helped you . It worked for a while .
But now your sickness is back
and you blame them for fucking you up .
- [ Lights buzzing ] - Madison : No . No .
It 's not me .
Stop lying to us .
I 'm telling the fucking truth !
[ Lights bursting ]
Regina : Shit !
[ Cell phone vibrating ]
He wants to talk to you .
[ Phone continues vibrating ]
You have got to be kidding me .
[ Static crackling ]
This is detective Shaw .
[ Electronic feedback shrills ]
Gabriel : Hello , detective .
Who am I talking to ?
Gabriel : You know who I am . You found me .
I didn 't find you soon enough .
But you found my things . I want them back .
Why was your stuff in her attic , hmm ?
You trying to incriminate her ?
Dumb bitch didn 't even know I was nesting in her home .
Is all this personal ?
If my blade had punched a hole in your face last night ,
would that have been personal ?
Who are you , Gabriel ?
Oh , I thought she had already told you .
I 'm a figment of her imagination .
[ Gabriel laughing maniacally ]
Ask her what she used to call me .
[ Static crackles , line disconnects ]
You see , Syd ? That 's why we never throw anything out .
You never know when something would come in handy .
Here .
Woman on phone : Yes , we had an Emily may .
She was remanded to our care
by the simion research hospital .
It says here they 've been shuttered since the 903 .
So it 's just been sitting there empty ?
Sorry , I don 't know . That was before my time .
[ Line beeps ]
[ Suspenseful music playing ]
[ Suspenseful music continues ]
[ Eerie music playing ]
- [ Muffled clattering ] - [ Gasps ]
[ Soft rattling ]
[ Sydney breathing heavily ]
Sydney : Records storage . Basement level .
Of course .
Please , officer . Officer ! I 'm not supposed to be here !
I haven 't done anything wrong !
I am not supposed to be here , god damn it !
They made a mistake .
[ { thud ] { Casps ]
[ Woman chuckling ]
- [ Urinating ] - Princess .
[ Indistinct chatter ]
[ Woman laughing ]
[ Sinister music playing ]
[ Grunts ]
Sydney : Emily may .
" The result of an absorption in utero ,
" growing in sync with patient ... "
[ Objects clattering ]
Today , we 'll be speaking to the subjects ' mother ,
Serena may .
15 years of age .
Poor girl was raped and carried her pregnancy to term .
She 's decided to entrust her children to our care .
This could be a phenomenal opportunity
to further our research .
Now , are you sure you want to do this , Serena ?
It 's okay , there 's no judgment here .
Mama won 't help me .
She called my pregnancy a transgression against god .
I don 't know how to look after them on my own .
[ Sighs ]
He 's an abomination .
I don 't know what else to do , doctor .
Please look after Emily .
Dr. Weaver : Don 't worry . You can have peace of mind
knowing we I ! Provide the best medical care .
They told me that she died while giving birth .
Those lying cock-knockers . [ Sighs ]
Dr. Weaver : Now , we ' re just going to need you
and your mother to sign some papen / vork .
[ EKG beeping ]
When will she wake up ?
She 's in a coma , detective . It 's in god 's hands .
Regina : Hey , you were right about the underground .
Jane Doe was a tour guide down there .
Employee of the month .
Kekoa : Serena may .
This is Madison 's birth mother .
Dr. Weaver : Emily , are you okay ?
Are you scared ?
Well , don 't be . He won 't wake up , ipromise .
I 've given him a heavy sedative .
It 's probably why you 're feeling sleepy too .
We just wanted a private moment with you
without Gabriel listening in .
We 've noticed in recent weeks you 've become more aggressive .
Can you tell us why ?
[ Whimpers softly ]
He 's been telling me to do things .
Bad things . To hurt people .
Dr. Weaver : Is that why you attacked Bobby fey ?
But Bobby 's twice your size .
Gabriel makes me strong .
He told me to kill Bobby .
Dr. Weaver : He actually said those words ?
Sometimes he speaks words ...
And other times , the words are in my head .
Then they aren 't really words anymore .
Just feelings .
But I knew what he wanted me to do .
He pretends to be nice .
But he 's the devil .
Dr. Weaver : Okay .
I 'm going to wake him up .
Why don 't you come around after I 've injected him ?
- — [ Madison whimpers ] - [ Liquid squirts ]
[ Madison gasps ]
- [ Screeching ] - [ Ominous music playing ]
- [ Both gasp ] - Oh , my god !
Oh , god !
Sydney : Oh , my god ! Maddy !
Dr. Weaver : So what exactly is Gabriel ?
Gabriel is an extreme version of a teratoma .
A tumor consisting of tissues , hair , teeth , muscles , bones .
But more specifically , in this case ,
it 's a parasitic twin .
When two embryos develop in the womb
don 't separate like they should ,
one twin is dominant ,
while the other is underdeveloped .
It 's not considered conjoined
because the underdeveloped twin
is dependent on the body of the other .
Like a parasite , Gabriel feeds off Emily .
Woman 1 : What 's the matter , pollyanna ?
You get lost on the way to the country club ?
[ Laughter ]
Look , ldont want any trouble .
I don 't give a fuck what you want .
An apple .
Pig .
A Teddy bear .
We ' re starting to suspect that Gabriel
can somehow access the region to the brain
that process visual stimuli ,
and make Emily see what he wants her to see .
This would explain her recent claims
of hallucinations and waking dreams .
[ Grunts ]
Woman 1 : What the fuck did you do to get in here ?
Forget to separate the recycling ?
[ Laughter ]
But I 'm willing to play nice for a price .
[ Gasping ]
What you got ?
Madison : [ Grunts ] Guard !
Woman 2 : Bitch .
[ { both grunting ] — [ Madison groaning ]
[ Woman 1 laughs ]
- — [ Screeching ] - [ Madison screaming ]
Gabriel , stop it .
[ Machine whirring ]
[ Bursting ]
[ Lights bursting ]
[ Madison grunting ]
- [ Squelching ] - What the fuck ?
[ Grunting convulsively ]
Woman 2 : Oh , shit .
Yo , this bitch is having a seizure .
Because they literally share the same brain ,
I think he 's able to trick her mind
and make her think she 's living her life as usual .
Essentially , placing her in a mental prison .
When in reality ,
Gabriel has hijacked her body and is using it himself .
[ Screams ]
[ Gasps and screams ]
It 's time to cutout the cancer .
Gabriel 's parasitic nature has increased significantly
as he 's now siphoning more fluids and nutrients ,
resulting in severe weight loss .
So Dr. Fields , Dr. Gregory , and myself have concluded ,
the only way to save Emily is to excise the teratoma .
Now , Gabriel is conjoined at the brain ,
so full removal could kill Emily
or result in permanent brain damage .
Course of action would be to remove what we can
and suppress the rest into her skull .
Let 's close her up .
[ Screaming ]
[ Squelching ]
[ All screaming ]
- — [ Growls ] - [ Gasps ]
[ Madison screaming ]
[ Growls ]
What the fuck ?
[ Screams ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Women whimpering ]
Holy shit ! Oh , god damn !
[ Bones cracking ]
[ Bones snap ]
[ { women continue whimpering ] { Bones cracking ]
[ All screaming ]
[ Groans ]
[ Screams ]
Woman 3 : Get me outta here !
Guard ! Get the motherfuckin ' guard !
- [ Neck snaps ] - Guard !
[ Woman 4 screams ]
Hey ! Open the motherfuckin ' door !
[ Yelps ]
[ Groaning ]
Holy shit ! Hey !
[ Guard grunting ]
[ Guard groaning ]
[ Cell phone ringing ]
Sydn ey : Keh ? Listen .
Gabriel is inside of Madison .
He 's been using her this whole time .
He 's been controlling her body like a puppet .
Whoa , whoa , whoa , Sydney , slow down .
You 're not making any sense .
Sydney : I found Madison 's history .
She was born with a parasitic twin .
Gabriel has been dormant all of these years .
When Derek smashed Madison 's head
against the wall , it woke Gabriel up .
- Bitch ! - [ Grunts ]
Jeez , Sydney , that 's insane .
Madison 's birth mother is still alive , keh . They lied .
I know . She 's the woman
who fell out of Madison 's attic .
We sent her to Seattle medical .
Are you kidding me ? We have to talk to her .
She 's the only person left alive who knows anything .
[ Muffled clanging ]
- [ Muffled shouting ] - [ Running footsteps ]
Man : [ Muffled ] It 's in the stairs , quick !
[ Muffled clang ] { Man screaming ]
[ Muffled thudding ]
- [ Gunshots ] - [ Gasps ]
- It 's coming from inside . - Kekoa : Shit .
I gotta go . I gotta go .
Keh ? Keh ?
[ Tires screeching ] { Car horn honking ]
[ Ominous music playing ]
[ Electricity buzzing ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Suspenseful music playing ]
[ Pants ]
[ Lights buzzing ]
[ Gasps ] Oh , god .
[ Both gasp ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Screams ]
[ Snarls ]
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Shit ! We 're getting shot at !
Stay back .
[ Grunting ]
We need backup .
Send the national fucking guard !
[ Screaming ]
Madison !
[ Rousing music playing ]
Kekoa : Madison !
[ Gabriel growls ]
[ Kekoa groaning ]
Get off him , motherfucker !
[ Groaning ] Fuck !
[ Gunshot ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Kekoa groaning ]
[ Regina groans ]
Oh , my god .
Okay . Fuck .
Told you not to get your ass kicked .
[ { both groaning ] — regina : Okay .
[ Grunts ]
[ Dramatic music playing ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Growls ]
[ Breathing shakily ]
- Regina . - [ Kekoa coughs ]
Oh , my god , kekoa !
[ Keypad beeping ]
Why am I calling the police ?
Call paramedics . Now !
Oh , reg ...
[ Both groaning ]
Oh , my god .
The mother , she 's going for her .
The hospital . You gotta go .
I 'll stay with her . It 's okay . Paramedics are on the way .
I 'll be fine . Now go stop him .
[ Elevator bell dings ]
Officer : Sorry , ma 'am , this area is restricted .
Right , I know , officer ,
but if you could just call detective kekoa Shaw ,
then he can fill you in . Just tell him Sydney lake is here .
I 'm sorry . Nobody is allowed in here .
I cannot let you by unless detective Shaw is here with ...
[ Electrical whining ]
[ Stifled groan ]
- What 's wrong ? Are you okay ? - [ G roans ]
Oh , my god . Oh , my god . Oh , my god .
Are you having a heart attack ?
- My pacemaker . - Okay .
- It 's burning . - [ Electrical buzzing ]
[ Pained scream ]
- Please go get help . - Okay .
- [ Gunshot ] - [ Groans ]
[ Sydney screams ]
[ Sydney panting ]
[ Screams ]
[ Groaning ]
Sydney !
[ Electronic feedback whines ]
Gabriel : I was saving you for last .
[ Yelps ]
[ Electricity bursting ]
[ Yelping ]
Gabriel : She chose you ...
[ Sydney screaming ]
Her own flesh and blood .
I should have killed you before you were born !
[ Yells ]
Gabriel , no !
[ Gasping ]
Gabriel .
[ Growls ]
Please forgive me .
I should never have given you away .
You were my son .
And I should have loved you no matter what .
[ Grunts ]
- [ Grunts ] — serena : Emily !
No ! No ! No ! You 're hurting her !
- [ G rowls ] - Sydney , get outta here !
[ Grunts ] { Sydney screams ]
[ Groans ]
[ Breathes shakily ]
Gabriel : Go on .
- Madison ? - Gabriel : Shoot me !
Madison , I know you 're in there .
Gabriel : And kill her .
What did you do to my sister ?
She 's not your sister !
[ Screams and groans ]
Sydney !
[ Screams ]
- [ Snarls ] - Maddy , please .
Gabriel : She can 't hear you .
Maddy , I know you can hear me . You have to fight him .
Gabriel : Madison 's not home .
Madison , he killed your babies .
He was the cause of your miscarriages .
He was feeding off of your fetuses
to build himself back up .
Maddy , please , please come back .
[ Groans ]
[ Rousing music playing ]
[ Bones crack ]
Gabriel : Goodbye , sis .
Gabriel , no !
- [ Gunshot ] - [ Gasps , sobbing ]
Gabriel : I wanted you to see ...
No , Gabriel . Please .
What you made me .
I 'm so sorry .
[ Muffled grunting ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Muffled groaning ]
[ Beeping rate increasing ]
[ Muffled whimpering ]
[ Beeping rapidly ]
[ Flatlining ]
Gabriel : A monster .
Madison : No , Gabriel .
You were always a monster .
[ Rustling ]
Gabriel : What ?
What 's happening ?
Madison ...
[ Grunts ]
[ Echoing ] Now I can do all the mind tricks you can .
[ EKG beeping steadily ]
Gabriel : No .
Not possible !
Did you forget we share the same brain ?
I didn 't ask to be tethered to you .
You don 't deserve your body .
I can use it better than you .
Not anymore .
You don 't get to control me ever again .
It 's over , Gabriel .
I 'm taking it all back .
My mind , my body , my everything .
Now you get to live in a world that I create .
[ Gabriel grunts ]
You can 't lock me in here forever .
You 'll always be stuck with me .
Sooner or later I will get out .
I know , but next time I 'll be ready for you .
[ Gasps deeply ]
[ G roans loudly ]
[ Grunts , wheezes ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Wheezing ] — [ Gabriel wails ]
[ Madison groaning ]
[ Gasping ]
Maddy ?
Maddy ? Is that you ?
Sydney , I 'm so sorry .
I 'm gonna lift this off you .
No , it 's too heavy .
It was always my body .
If he was strong enough to do this , then so am I.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Groans ]
Sydney : [ Softly ] Hey . Hey .
Hey , stay with me . Hey .
Hey , look at me . Hey .
[ Soft music playing ]
[ Sydney sniffling ]
[ Crying ]
All my life , I 've yearned
for a blood connection with someone .
Yet in the end , it was right in front of me all along .
Blood or not , you will always be my sister .
And I will always love you .
[ Soft music continues ]
[ Electrical buzzing ]
[ Sinister music playing ]